Should you eat to live or live to eat?... a question posed by French playwright Moliere in his work ‘The Miser’.
人应该为了活着而吃饭，还是为了吃饭而活着？这是法国剧作家莫里哀在其作品《吝啬鬼》中提出的问题。
While eating is functional, and our bodies need the fuel that food provides, dining with friends or loved ones can be a wonderful experience.
吃饭固然具有实际功用，我们的身体也需要食物提供的能量，但与亲友一同用餐，也可以是一段十分美好的经历。
However, some of us often find ourselves reserving a table for one in a restaurant.
不过，我们中有些人却常常会在餐厅里预订单人餐桌。
But is dining alone really that bad?
但独自用餐真的有那么糟糕吗？
Maybe not.
或许并非如此。
We all have foods we like and dislike. Maybe it’s a pungent cheese or stinky fish.
每个人都有自己爱吃和不爱吃的东西，可能是气味浓烈的奶酪，也可能是腥味很重的鱼。
We sometimes hold back on things that may offend the noses of others.
有些食物可能会让别人觉得刺鼻，我们有时就会克制自己不去吃。
When dining alone, we can consume whatever we like, with the added bonus that we might be able to eat more healthily.
但独自用餐时，你可以随心所欲地吃任何想吃的东西，而且还有一个额外的好处——你或许能吃得更健康。
Often, if you want a salad and your significant other wants some less healthy cuisine, you end up ordering the same.
很多时候，如果你想吃沙拉，而你的伴侣却想吃些没那么健康的菜肴，最后你们很可能会点一样的东西。
And if you don’t get the same, you might end up with food envy as you watch someone chow down on a pizza while you’re left holding the lettuce.
就算你们点的不一样，看着别人大快朵颐地吃着披萨，自己却只能啃着生菜，你也可能会产生“美食羡慕”的心情。
Have you ever spent too long debating with people which restaurant to eat in or when to meet?
你是否曾和别人花了很长时间争论去哪家餐厅吃饭、什么时候碰面？
If dining solo, you can make the choice depending on your culinary desires at that moment and get your nourishment at exactly the time you’re hungry!
如果是独自用餐，你可以完全根据当下的饮食欲望做决定，在自己饿的时候准时补充营养！
And why does it have to be a restaurant?
而且为什么非得去餐厅呢？
You could eat in a park, garden or even your bed – the point is, the choice is yours!
你可以去公园、花园，甚至在床上吃——关键是，选择权在你自己手里！
That alone time also means it’s a time to switch off.
这段独处的时光，也是一段能让你彻底放松的时光。
According to psychologist Sherrie Bourg Carter, a bit of solitude can help your brain to unwind and may help you concentrate more.
心理学家雪莉·伯格·卡特表示，适度的独处有助于大脑放松，还能提升专注力。
Finally, for some, dining alone can be a necessity.
最后，对有些人来说，独自用餐是一种必需。
For those of us who suffer from misophonia, a hatred of sound, that can in some cause PTSD, the noise of someone else masticating can be unbearable.
对于患有恐音症（一种对特定声音的厌恶感，严重时可能会引发创伤后应激障碍）的人而言，别人咀嚼食物的声音会让他们难以忍受。
Eating alone can save you from the extreme anxiety that may arise listening to someone smack their lips or the sloshing of saliva in their mouths!
独自用餐可以让他们免受煎熬——不用再因为听到别人咂嘴或是口腔里唾液晃动的声音而陷入极度焦虑！
So, is eating alone bad?
所以，独自用餐真的不好吗？
Well, it may not be for everyone, but there certainly are some benefits to it.
当然，它可能并不适合所有人，但确实有不少好处。
Try it sometime – you might just like it!
不妨找个时间试试看——说不定你会喜欢上这种方式呢！